all right welcome to the board meeting I
don't think we need to number them the
world Friday I don't know what number
this is our third or fourth but yeah
we're moving forward that's all that
matters and when someone else joins they
can just jump in wherever but they are
this one doesn't have usually tells us
how many people are on but I don't see
that here maybe it's cause no one's on
or it's also different YouTube and the
Facebook and periscope are all slightly
different in stream your idea how was I
have a we had committed last week to
comparing notes I think on the scheduler
was a scheduler specific or was it just
all of the features and benefits
features the goal was mostly the
scheduler because that's the the piece
we kind of know we need but if you have
other ideas we can also discuss all
right yeah my brain likes to do it all
as opposed to you know which pieces are
just the scheduler but I had it broken
down I was trying to do it the
individual piece of like what the
individual account needs and then what
like the system needs and then it kind
of got broken down further into what the
individual Ike what we need before
someone comes from India cafe during the
idea cafe and then after the voting and
then a bit of the individual and bigger
one so it's like six different things
that aren't quite right some of them are
all interconnected but were you able to
sit down with it this week or I was not
but I think as we go through your ideas
I will be reminded of the things I
thought of earlier so I think will be
good okay so the time zone coordination
is a big one just being able to
coordinate between time zones that I get
it in my time zone and you get it in
your time zone and then because we might
want to try different iterations of what
the idea cafe is having having the
ability to play with the time slot where
it starts and goes for a duration right
so it's
consistently set up to be a half an hour
but maybe we want it to go past like I
don't want to cut people off at half an
hour because often you're still in the
middle of the sentence you're still kind
of winding down at the end of half an
hour and so potentially based on what
people are using this for they might
want to go for an hour time slot or
maybe even a four hour time slot if
they're working at with a very specific
group on something so just being able to
so then that was just notes in
particular the individual piece for the
individual accounts I have here that the
individual to put in their total
availability so kind of like we did with
the doodle poll right like right across
the board here's our like my
availability and so the scheduler to be
able to compare those and then schedule
people write that if it's gonna be more
broad be put in the topics of interest
that I want to be alerted to if there's
something in my availability that is
available to me right I don't need to
especially if it gets big it's Facebook
we don't want to be in I don't want to
know every time there's a conversation
but I want to know when there's
conversations the people that I'm
interested in or the topics I'm
interested in they're within my time
frame and then the invitation piece that
they need to be able to get the link so
in the especially the beginning and
where we're not Facebook people aren't
going to know to check it so to be able
to email them right to be able to say to
be able to connect them on their phones
or email a way for them to be able to
know yes we've scheduled you now for a 2
p.m. one and possibly I'm just this just
coming to me now that I think we all
have a slightly different tell me I do
want me to slow down by the way you're
taking notes no I'm keeping up with you
at the top is that one is I get to say
how many um like if maybe by weeks wide
open schedule me 24/7
but I only want to talk for three
conversations of half an hour right so
be able to put in my overall
availability and also my preferences for
the maximum number of conversations and
there was another piece of that oh how
much what's the word how much in advance
I want to know about it right it could
be hey there's a conversation happening
right now if you're interested in it or
maybe I prefer to know a week in advance
or 24 hours in advance and if it could
be individually scheduled for the person
then people who like having that last
minute can't come on and be like hey I
five minutes my kids nappy and I can
come on for half an hour right and other
people want it to be more so having that
that diversity of individual preferences
I heard you said the invitation number
of conversations per week I have on here
and then that other piece we had kind of
talked about last week of like as an
individual what I need to have in a
conversation and maybe what I want to
have in a conversation so a need for me
it actually kind of goes in-between
because I could theoretically have a
conversation with somebody who's on
voice but it's gonna be much more taxing
for my brain I prefer it to be on video
so I'd prefer everyone at my table to be
on video other people are gonna have the
opposite preference or they want
everyone to be on voice or they want to
be on voice and they don't care what
anyone else is on I imagine with
different disabilities and with
different just diversity there's gonna
be different things that people need or
want so just being able to even just
type it in so we can include in the next
iteration right my need is to not have
this at English because I speak
Cantonese right like whatever it happens
to be we can then see a way like if you
don't I mean how do people put it in
Cantonese and therefore we could that
would be our next focus for opening up a
new language probably just having
languages languages you speak that you
would like to have these conversations
and right it's going to start with just
English but the more people who speak
English and then also speak a second
language what's our secondary one that
we want to open up and that's a big key
so that also isn't on here is that
threshold of use of workability where
like right now I've coordinated I don't
know if you saw for the idea cafe game B
I just put out a like one page document
what the idea Cafe is and a spreadsheet
for the ongoing because it's gonna be a
new URL link if you want to participate
right just like those new URL link for
this every week and then there's a
different link if you want to just watch
and I don't want to have
send that out to every individual like
find out the people who are
participating and then send that out to
them so I'm like you guys coordinated
right here's the document you look at it
right you look at it see that I've put
the link there and they click on it and
first-come-first-serve whoever's there
is there for the idea Cafe that's not
gonna work so well with our platform but
it's for for enough Spanish Ernesto yes
in Spanish out of curiosity Ernesto if
it was in Spanish would you be willing
to do it on video or would you be doing
it on voice or would you still prefer
just typing because there's also that
and I think there's a lot of people who
do prefer just typing but I also feel
there's a lot of things out there that
are typing like if you like connection
through typing there are a ton of
avenues to get that I don't find
connections through typing I need it to
be voice or video in order to I don't
know comprehend that it's a human being
on the other line and feel that
connection right whereas other people
don't feel safe like that and they want
to have typing but to just know that
some people are like that and maybe
there's a way to integrate all of those
where for some people who don't mind
being at a table with voice video and
typing that it would I guess he said I
don't know if you see it I guess it
depends on the participants put it up
here yeah which makes sense and that's a
big piece about it's like how safe do
you feel right you might start out that
you want to just watch and then but
other people might not be feel safe with
you watching so having the ability at
the table to record it the ability at
the table to say whether you're
comfortable having people watch it
right I'd be comfortable with people
watching it depending on the topic some
topics may be less so-and-so needs
someone so as the individual and then I
have it broken down a bit here on what
we would want before somebody
participated during the participation a
few of the features and the voting and
the after so for before I thought that
an intro video something that explains
what an idea Cafe is that what you're
expected to watch before coming on so we
don't have to have the intro every time
what this is and what this looks like
as well as a video if we have our terms
and conditions I would like that to be
in a video format to be like okay this
is what just so you know you can get
triggered this can be emotionally like
it's a video it's only a video like
whatever our legalese has to be having
it more in a video like you know what
you're signing up for and at the same
time we want to continually improve it
but this is all of ours right what do
you call it again terms and conditions
is what I own and those would probably
be two separate ones were you like hey
if you watched the terms and conditions
or read it if you want to but like we've
made it an easy language for you to
watch as well to expect that people have
actually done it unlike every time I
check off the box and have in no way
read the terms and conditions but
especially since it is it's
simultaneously something that can stir
up a lot of emotions and be quite
traumatizing and at the same time is
only a conversation right so like
knowing to set up the person for success
for like this could happen so you're
aware and getting feedback right what
what was what I don't want is people to
sue right to come on like a normal
platform that we own and they don't and
we're in responsible for their
experience and then they sue because it
wasn't the experience they wanted not
saying that couldn't possibly happen but
like the idea is it's our platform right
so just like if I hurt your feelings
right here you could come and sue me but
that's not really gonna I don't have any
money Bentley comes nobody pays you sue
yeah but like you don't I mean there's a
different energy when it's a small group
or a different energy when we know it's
our project and that's what I want
everyone to feel this is our project if
something doesn't work for you come be
part of fixing it right come be part of
making it better so that that doesn't
happen was it the people at the table
was it the question was it you know what
I mean like to empower people to know
that it it's not that your experience
didn't matter but it's that it we are
not responsible for your experience and
yet everyone's responsible for
everyone's experience at the same time
like how can we improve it so that it
keeps improving getting better
all right this is uh or Nestle's
conversation to put up popped up here
like a one on one or five on one meaning
proportion how much each participant can
or is expected to participate and yeah
that's a piece of both the intro video I
believe as well as the iterations right
that like that is a good some people the
idea cafe isn't meant to be a one-on-one
conversation but there might be a tool
for like oh we had conflict maybe
there's a way to walk through without
there being a third person a way to
resolve that conflict
it's almost automated and then that gets
too much and it's escalated to like a
more it's a host or something or just I
say I love the three people idea cafes
those are my favorite ones and so maybe
I set my parameter to that's what I
would like and other people who are more
introverted and would like to listen
more than they talk my prefer a four
percent or a five percent and so that's
part of the diversity I think of saying
how many people you prefer I'm also okay
having a one-on-one other people won't
be because there's more focus on them as
well as more if something goes wrong and
it's not being recorded he-said she-said
right like she said they said they said
like the piece of that and so I think
think you are not so important piece and
sorry during the intro video the idea
Cafe on YouTube isn't really set up that
somebody passes but it's also allowed
right if you want to be part of the
conversation but you don't want to share
in the first five minutes that's allowed
if you're just someone who would rather
listen more than speak you're still
allowed to speak but you don't have to
write it this isn't a in fact it's
almost the opposite you don't want to um
oh yeah another that's it good interrupt
it well and that's part of the needs and
wants right if you're someone who gets
really triggered by people interrupting
you maybe there's one that's like zero
interruption and other ones like me and
my brother tomorrow were like when the
third person joins us we're gonna have
to learn how to not interrupt each other
because our family dynamic is very keep
speaking until the other one jumps in it
is like there is no way to not do that
between us so that was before the video
so before
people even sign up to get them set up
for success that they know what this is
even having one of like hey you can
watch one on a topic you're interested
in right so that one that has been
recorded right now that is the YouTube
channel right like go there look at the
what what's already there or like a rule
of make a button yeah I like that
which allows you to interrupt the other
speaker to make sure you are
understanding or just like put up your
hand right so I don't really even
interrupt you but you're like I have a
question and that might be added to the
jury like during a conversation the
features that would be good and we had
talked about the the Talking Stick
feature may be called something
different but the Talking Stick we're
also well you're talking you're
effectively you have it and everyone
else is muted but if I don't shut up and
I'm just talking for 20 minutes it's not
designed that way it's designed to be
five minutes but it keeps flashing hey
it's been five minutes and I keep
talking you know I mean that there's a
way to maybe override that there's a way
for the group to without them just
leaving maybe kicking me out I don't
know unless the feature is just after
five minutes it goes to the next person
cut you off half sentence which could be
right that could be part of what we try
and this is the point is to have I'm not
the coder I'm in no way it capable of
doing that but like how easy is it to
put in there's the beta and then there's
the iterations right and so the
iterations if they're designed that we
know that that could be it's part of the
design in the beginning to have it as
simple as possible and then when
someone's like I would like to cut them
off mid-sentence we can try that and
when someone's like I don't want to be
cut off in sentence we can try that and
have the the diversity of what it is and
so that was jury on a timer like a
literal timer and if I would rather not
see it while I'm talking maybe I can
turn mine off but knowing that I'm how
close to five minutes I've gotten is is
good this isn't really a jury not this
would be powerful not so much in the
beta but later on I don't know if I've
mentioned this before is stats like just
like how much I talked in the 30 minutes
right like that would be part of voice
recognition like even if it wasn't and
that would be again a feature of is
everyone at the table comfortable doing
that but I think there's so much
information in the data there that we'd
never
have access to like how much do I
monopolize a conversation versus what I
think I monopolize and what is actually
is very different how much do I
interrupt people anyone and how much do
I interrupt like men versus women people
of color versus you know people I
perceive as white like like saying is
that I'm not gonna be consciously
thinking of like I'm not like oh I can
interrupt this person no problem it's
gonna be that subconscious underlining
that I would I would person like to have
access to information
I wouldn't necessarily want you to have
access to my information unless we were
part of a conversation it was just hey
Jubilee spoke for 20 of the 30 minutes
unless there was a really good reason to
do that I need to own that and
monopolize less what this symbol I think
people should be able to assemble
conversation rules themselves yeah that
would be great
especially in later iterations but just
like is what I was talking about earlier
the threshold of usability out that to
begin with
if we have 12 people on the on it not
everyone's gonna be able to have a
conversation that works for them
we're back we're not really doing the
platform with 12 people we're building
the YouTube channel until there's enough
interest hopefully to like build
something that already has a number of
people interested but then so let's say
we're building it for game B
specifically or fright ends for together
text specifically then we have maybe 500
a population of 500 that we then want is
scheduled throughout a week right so
we're not gonna want to schedule a 24/7
conversation there isn't gonna be the
threshold of people there to hold that
interest and same with when we first
start in a new category when we first
start in a new language right if there's
if there's five people who want to speak
Spanish we can set them up right away if
they all at the same time zone right oh
sorry they all have the same schedule
and areas of interest but as we branch
into new ones we want to make sure the
threshold of people is interesting
enough to make that usable right like
scheduling one a week as opposed to you
know you might show up and have one
other person if that makes sense like
making sure that and I think part of
that is also in the rules of assembly of
a conversation that the more niche I
need to get on a converse
for me the less likely I'm to be able to
find people but when there's millions of
people on it if that happens then
yeah sky's the limit right then I can
have all of my needs and wants met in my
language in my timezone in the area of
interest that I want and it can tell me
like oh well if you opened up your
language you could speak to so many more
people hmm too bad I can't like I don't
speak but like if you open up your time
period right if you open up your to be
able to show me that expansion kind of
like when you buy a airplane ticket and
you're staying on this state but it's
like but if you went on this state it
could be this much cheaper right like to
kind of I don't know what that would
look like visually but wherever you're
able to coordinate the conversation hey
if you if you if you were willing to be
on video there's more people available
right if you were willing to not be on
video there's more people creating a
meta conversation assembly - and that's
what like I mean that would be ideal
that this tool could be used for anyone
who wants to have any conversation
brings in the people but it's just the
beta has a very specific and it will be
very focused right so that it's easier
cheaper you don't know what's starting
and then builds out from from there
mm-hmm
and then so that was the jury and I
think that was a lot of stuff that comes
up as I'm talking yeah the vote so the
other thing is we want to be able to not
just say your areas of interest but then
how do we generate a question for people
to have a conversation around and part
of the iteration is there might be times
when we're not having a question right
that people prefer not to have a
question to answer and they prefer just
open dialogue but the idea Cafe is very
specifically designed around a question
right now and so how do we craft a
converse how do we craft a question and
that's about maybe a different video or
a different learning period of um here's
what a good question is right and then
we have the feedback into the system of
here's questions that have actually
worked in the past right these have been
people have voted these the most
enjoyable to participate in these ones
have been the most productive and we can
kind of see the crafting of a question
and we might even be able to auto
auto-generate them to start with not to
start start but you know what I mean
once we have data just to do it to start
with and then the humans take it and
make it better to improve on it so how
if you'll be able to submit questions
and improve on questions and vote on
them to say yes especially with the
threshold in the beginning like for game
B Tuesdays at 11:30 we're having one
question rights and then the next week
we have a question in the next week and
they might repeat because they might be
there's new people and we want to have
the same like this week's one is what
it's game be mean to you because it's a
very easy one for game be people that
anyone could answer it's there's not a
right or wrong there's probably gonna be
more niche ones that some people are
gonna want to talk about and some people
aren't and so I'm using that tool that
the meet the meeting tool that we had
done in order to ask people like say
what a question is that you want and
then have people vote on them but having
that of course into the system so people
can easily generate especially during a
question during a conversation right
they can think of one inch and hey this
is a lead on to this and even with them
metadata might be the wrong word but
like hey in order to have this
conversation you might have needed to
have the previous conversation right it
might need to build build on the
previous one and the other ones will be
one-off no you don't need to some might
be experts right you need to kind of
prove that you like this is more for
meeting people's personal needs I want
to talk to other scientists in this area
about this question right um I'll be
very powerful I want to talk to other
people who've had this experience even
if I haven't maybe I'm thinking to
becoming a parent I want to talk to
other parents about their their
questions as long as it's transparent
right that um I'm not a parent but I
want to talk to other parents and other
people are willing to do that around me
because that would be clearly a-- i have
questions asked this is too many
iterations of this thing but if these
things are real and then after after
you've had the conversation for the user
to be able to rate the question right
the both the question and the
conversation and the people so how
effective or enjoyable was that
conversation to talk about you know
we're just giving feedback how was the
time period how was talking for five
minutes how
the experience for you as well as how
are the people right not so that we're
kicking people out necessarily unless
people are truly horrific and but so
that we can match them more with
compatibility right you don't seem to
like people who interrupt you may we
suggest the non interruption button
right you seem to really like
interrupting people maybe suggest the
interruption button right like having
that that piece that isn't excluded or
including and it's saying how compatible
people at the table are and you're gonna
be more likely to be maybe in the
beginning it's literally just vote up
vote down where we cannot guarantee you
unless you block someone we can't
guarantee you're not gonna be at a table
with them but I enjoy talking to these
people more than I enjoy talking to
these people and so it's more likely to
match me with people who you know it's
starting like almost like circles like
here are the people you really like to
talk to and they're available hey would
you like to talk to them and otherwise
building out from there yeah that is the
notes going so fast if you talk as well
he's taking notes talking about mine
does he I talk a lot I do eventually
talk tag okay I shouldn't of adding
subject tags in real time you can
navigate tags or nested you mean like
well you're having a conversation
recording it we can say hey like we're
talking about the Dunbar number here and
someone contending it cuz I'd be cool if
it's being recorded and then other
people are watching it and you can find
all the Dunbar you know number ones or
that I don't know what he's referring to
but check that well that's the same way
the tag clouds are shown in many
WordPress sites how how hot each tag has
been through time yeah and see like what
questions generate the most participants
what time periods for generate the most
participants like having that data is
very very important so a tag link to a
chronological timeline could be very
interesting I know what that means but
you probably do yeah I just if I wanted
to to see every time
I spoke then maybe there would be a way
to be able to do that the kind of like
video comments to take appearances at
certain times ya know that kind of like
I'm doing here I guess tagging the
comments but that being said mostly this
isn't happening right we're having a
conversation someone happens to be
watching so they can feel comfortable or
they participate
it wouldn't be interacting I don't think
with the comment section but maybe maybe
that is something people like and they
like having someone you know offering
offering things yeah yeah one of the
features that kind of thing is also you
know maybe we after the video we'd want
to have that kind of take away I can't
remember what you call it but it it's
where you're gathering that the nuggets
out of the out of the meeting do you
mean more like the taking notes portion
so that it can be like fed up or do you
mean more like like this 30 seconds was
being able to take off this 30 seconds
of video and share it well it's thinking
just kind of notes and textual stuff
yeah I can't I can't think that a video
clip would actually provide enough value
of the context so I think people have to
rephrase it that would be something
where if you're willing to be watched by
people my guess is they're like I don't
like taking notes that's why I'm not
taking notes I like taking notes on
paper and then I really appreciate that
other people do and yet also I
understand some a lot of times in a
meeting nobody wants to take notes but
somebody is willing to and to I think
there can be medians for no one's taking
notes that's fine just know that that's
not gonna happen if you're not taking
notes and you're not no one is um you're
not recording it there's no way it kind
of harder to sit besides in the minds
and hearts of the people moving forward
and that's fine but then you can't go
back and and bring it out after right
and you can you can feel like I was part
of this amazing conversation but you
can't not in the same way as if it's
recorded and people are able the minute
again people are able to like there
could be participants like someone did
kind of go through the communism Marxism
ones and kind of say here's what I think
each of you are saying I was like that's
really cool thank you
they're cool like I did watch all of
those by the way was interesting say
that in October take Dunbar number was
discussed twenty times yes a kind of
mystics on whether that's I don't know
how hard that is would be for like do we
need to record it for that to happen do
we need it to I mean I yeah there
wouldn't be I guess so I did make a note
that afterwards on the after features
that we might want to then kind of tag
if it's going to be recorded you know
I'm sorry if it's going to be made
public than tagging it actually I put it
in there so then that could be something
that then you can pull those statistics
out of mm-hmm yeah I just like if AI
could do it right if it was like
automatic if I say Dunbar number it just
takes it even though I'm not really
talking about Dunbar number I'm just
using this example or something that
could be tagged right and cuz I said it
somebody like actually it's not it's
like one out of five stars relevant
right versus something awe-inspiring Lee
knew that I should not be a scholar on
the Dunbar number is like Wow five stars
that's relevant you know I can like
mm-hm
pull them automated automated transcript
sir are beginning to be rather accurate
so yeah I could definitely be a thing
because if it's able to subtitle in real
time that would be amazing because
wanted it adds to the language like
people who can't who who English is
their second language having subtitles
is huge being hard of hearing subtitles
are huge for basically anything just
helps you translate it it helps you do
to help the metadata it's also something
that I find really like I don't subtitle
my videos even though I really wish they
were subtitled like I want them to be
but it takes a lot of time and effort
and there isn't a way like when I'm
watching a YouTube video and the
subtitle is off
I'm like why can't I just correct it
like why can't I just be like without
having to go in and do this whole big
meta thing it should be as easy as ok I
corrected it and if you know what I mean
avi correct it and I'm a troll and I
corrected a horrible way that we don't
even if three people correct it it's
good right that like that becomes the to
make it easier easier for people to do
that's it
for people to optionally check well
there is its original conversation and
concept would be to create incremental
self-correcting conversations I think
there was a one before that that I'm
missing imagine if you could go back to
video conversations and insert your own
video comments that's also cool because
when I'm rewatching myself a lot of
times I'll be like because I'm trying to
say 15 things at once and then I'm like
oh I didn't even get to the point and so
to be able to go in and put that would
be would be amazing and so what Jim rat
does that with his shows easy goes back
and puts comments and you see that in
YouTube videos if people being like
actually I had that information wrong
here it is right um it's it's less about
disseminating information and therefore
it doesn't almost matter if it's right
but to be able to go in and maybe tag
hey and then I talked about this this
other time or hey I reference this
conversation here's the tag to that
conversation but the point isn't
necessarily to make YouTube that's
interactive it's to make an experience
for the person that is changing them and
like for the individual be able to
participate in a meaningful intimate
conversation and then all of the
information we can get out of that yeah
let's get that information out because
it helps us make the system better it
helps us make some of us are just data
geeks and we like that kind of thing you
know
like it's just a lot of a lot of
information and as long as we're
transparent about it about about it and
there's an option to opt-in and opt-out
I think the more data the better yeah
think that's great I yeah I think that's
getting a bit far afield from the
original our goal is really that
experience and and the after stuff is
all kind of bonus and that and that's
getting really kind of complex
afterwards stuff I do like the idea in
general of being able to take splice
videos and splice in other comments and
stuff that would be an interesting
project in and of itself yeah so what
I'm seeing here is that especially for
like the scheduling is that an estimate
syntax I think most of the stuff about
your your needs and your kind of
preferences all of that could be started
with as a tagging system and then as you
add a tag you could designate it as
being required or you know just a
preference so I think you'd get a lot of
the features in with that kind of one
feature and then of course the
scheduling being able to put your
calendar in there and then we have to
figure out notifications you mean like
literally upload by Kelly because I want
to be we need to be able to do both
things I don't have a calendar of a
paper copy that isn't gonna be able to
be uploaded but I can put in my schedule
right I'm available 9:30 to 2:30 when my
kids in school more or less unless I was
going grocery shopping and then you know
and that sorry that was also something
um as well as the preference of how long
like that I want to be scheduled I want
to be told there's a conversation 24
hours in advance or right away is is my
schedule constant mine is fairly
constant other people's isn't right
they're on shift work so they literally
need their their google calendar to be
uploaded to be like I'm working I'm not
available but on these time periods they
are and easier we make it for them
better so if they are able to just
upload their calendar that would be
amazing continually and also have a
feature this happens on dating sites
especially paid dating sites where
there's a ton of people who have their
information in there but they're not
active right so a certain amount of like
okay you haven't had a conversation
among
so we're assuming you're not actually
available for a conversation I don't
know if that's even needed because it's
literally like asking you hey do you
want to have this conversation in your
pinging back and as long as you keep
getting those and you want them you're
not unsubscribing that's fine but there
might be a reason to have that right to
be like yeah I mean if costs start in an
or having to pay for that communication
that notification and then yeah that
might be something we look into you
mm-hmm
yeah I know a dating sites you're like
oh look at all these people but no
because most of them aren't on here they
signed up then it was paid communication
and everyone dropped out so there's
maybe one tenth of the people that are
on there right so it hurts the
experience of the person who's actually
trying to use your service and might pay
for it if it didn't have all of this
overinflated community I don't know if
that's the same for us because again
maybe you're maybe you you do want to
pick a topic there's a bunch of people
in and all the people that are in there
somehow
exit exited but aren't available right
now but I think that this is a different
system and since we're creating it for
purpose a non-profit we don't have the
incentive to over inflate our numbers
right or not yeah look at us we have a
million people having conversations when
it's really a few hundred having actual
conversations yeah there's still a
tempted temptation to do that even if
you're not for profit just because you
want because people do like
participating something was something
that a lot of people are already
participating in but as long as we can I
think it's better in that case to appeal
to the early adopters but it's it's uh
it's tempting to exaggerate your numbers
yeah I mean can be a transparent about
like hey a million people have signed up
right like just use the language that is
real like a million people aren't
logging on every day but they're signed
up and potentially you know there's this
many people interested in that topic
like to be able to have more access to
data because it's our platform so it's
like what makes it better for you if
you're like I'm not using it because
there's only a hundred people on there
I personally have no problem with that
I'm like as long as I matched up with a
few people I care about the conversation
not the bigger one like I don't care a
Twitter would be awesome if it was just
game be people right like I'd be okay
with that
like its I don't need there to be the
millions of people and Donald Trump to
be on there and like I don't need the
people with millions of followers but
maybe I'm unique in that I think we're
also creating something unique where
it's like this isn't a fly-by-night
platform this isn't the new social media
that everyone's gonna jump on board and
then jump off of maybe it is but like
the idea is what would make you stay
what makes it enjoyable how do we
continually improve it because it's ours
we need a way to have a video
conversation if it's too combative and
there's too many trolls what's going on
how do we stop that if it's to anything
that goes wrong how do we fix it
together how do we make the next one
better yep yeah so I guess next steps
would be to kind of prioritize these and
figure out what's our minimum set now I
guess we already have a minimum set
cause we're already doing it right you
know so YouTube channel is the minimum
set yeah I guess what's the next
valuable piece I think that ability to
kind of put in your calendar and say
when you're available even more so than
the topics and the descriptions and
needs and stuff and then have it kind of
this this matching up of people who have
available time to meet yes yeah yeah and
also I'm sterna practice a mega rule
because my brains going into the next
conversation and not listening um how do
we want the first tool to work right is
it - what's the word like back up the
YouTube channel or is it to create
assume style conversation right and my
guess is it's a zoom style conversation
YouTube's more about bringing people
into the zoom style conversation most
people
aren't comfortable having their
conversation broadcasts that's a piece
of what I'm now offering people in the
idea cafe is afterwards the idea is with
a game be one we're gonna record it
unlisted so that people can watch who
aren't participating but from game be
write the if you got the link to the
participation you weren't able to
participate you can watch basically
right it's not open to everyone but it's
open to people who would have
participated and then afterwards the
people who participated get to say
whether or not it's deleted right
deleted private unlisted or public I
think that is a good feature to have
also in the one write that like maybe we
recorded it and then afterwards we want
to delete it but that's not the
conversation we're having um like add
new features the thing we haven't
prioritized yet that to be able to have
people come on board and have a
conversation either for together attack
our thing or game be the bigger thing
right um or which one fits in which one
it's hard to say but to find um like
what is needed and that's part of like
having the idea cafes on with game be
how how does this work how doesn't it
worked in order to know some of those
like I think it would be the big piece
you're right is the scheduler like
getting people to a conversation whether
it's on YouTube or not there's benefits
and costs to having it on YouTube right
there's a lot of people who don't want
to participate because it's on YouTube
they don't want to be visible to the
world even if it can be good and even
for v1 it may be with the scheduler it
may be like oh we've picked a time for
you someone else needs to get a free
account at zoom and and set it up and if
someone records it then you either stay
on and you leave in you and you allow
them to record it because you know we
can all agree whether it'll be deleted
or not but there's no way for us to
enforce it at this point yeah that's
important so there's four terms and
conditions yeah and we could yeah and we
could definitely make a terms and
conditions kind of video but it would be
it would be up to them to either watch
that I mean if depending on let me let
me take a step back so what I'm first
going
look for technologies that already
exists that meet that kind of minimum
set of needs see if there is some sort
of scheduling system out there we can
use what are its gaps before we kind of
dive in and start creating something and
so depending on that it will have to
just decide did that become maybe the
discussion for next meeting is was I was
able to find time to find anything and
then and then yeah we can talk about
where those features are whether we do
need to build something this track to do
this know which is a good I mean I'm not
the person to do that I'm not like even
doodle I'm like why why it doesn't
coordinator but like it's like doodle
meets Google calendars meets this and
that thing might already exist and also
it might be pieces from little pieces
from different ones that we do need to
create cuz it's hard to coordinate
pieces from from other things but if it
if it performs 80% of the task like
honestly having the document and the
spreadsheet does a lot of the work that
I was like I can't email all of you
individually and like what happened with
the communism Marxism one of like okay
this is hard to coordinate and people
don't show up and people though and I'm
like oh I'm just going to let go of
right not everyone's gonna get to
participate first-come first-serve
you've been for next week one of the
first like your spot is blocked because
I want you to participate in it right I
want you to be able to experience that
so that you understand it because you're
creating a platform for it right or
you're like part of the conversation
that creates the platform yeah I don't
need a spot except there's only six
spots and they're only five people can't
participate so I'm the host you're one
of them so there's four other people to
participate right whoever shows up and
is those four people is who's gonna be
on it other than that and the first week
is gonna be overly that's I don't want
to move to a zoom call which needs kind
of 12 people before there's a constant
enough group of people who want to have
participate once that happens then you
could open more time slots but I'm like
I don't want to open more time slots I'm
already having five conversations every
week that aren't the idea cafe that are
later all of these individual things
that are amazing why don't remember I'm
saying
that I've done like the 80% I guess like
this spreadsheet and the document feels
my needs for the 80 percents that I'm
not doing it doing all of this work but
semester so that I'll put up our
nestling and I want to interrupt a quick
observation that fix the world Friday
show seems based on we got a lot of time
left to fix the world
I take lesson is that on that yeah no it
does and also we don't have a lot of
time but we also do if we can like what
I propose that we fix the world with a
global tech cooperative once we have the
way to have a conversation once we have
a handful of tools like the scheduler
like a group coordination and we can
unleash humanity on humanity's problems
everything gets fixed so rapidly but
this is the snowball starting like this
is the slow part and it feels like we're
not moving fast enough but everyone's
willing to come on board and move us
faster right no you don't get to move
Jubilee and Bentley faster because we're
autonomous human beings who gets it like
have our own schedule but if someone
else has a way right of like hey I can
build that this weekend go for it right
like why not why not and if you know
that's kind of the idea is Ernesto had a
comment even before joining cells
content so to assemble a synchronous
conversations almost like video letters
where people take turns to assemble a
conversation exploring a certain subject
would be great I thought about that
because since we are doing things kind
of online we have the opportunity where
people aren't actually all doing this at
the same time but I think that would be
a slightly different concept than what
do you what you've been kind of thinking
of because you you want that kind of
immediate feedback from the audience but
I think I think that that's something to
consider in the future is and and I
don't know if you all have seen the
letters project where the they have a
website where you're supposed to write
to people
to have a conversation they write a
long-form letter back and forth about it
so it'd be similar to that but in in a
video form it sounds like what Arness
does this is also I don't know if you
guys are familiar I don't remember the
person who literally have any
conversation with him once have some
time because I don't think it's names on
there but the glass speed conversation
and they are creating an app for that
and it started video but it's it's the
idea is you have two people they can be
up to four and you're going back and
forth for a minute
so it's like I take a minute you take a
minute and then it's up to ten rounds so
it's a 10-minute conversation and
because it's this concentrated time
you're not bringing ego it's
theoretically you're not bring an ego
into it or a lot of I or filler language
like well I think that in my opinion
that you're like just focusing on the
thing that it is it's an amazing
experience to be part of and it kind of
leads this this cool conversation at the
end but yeah that's not quite what we're
making we're making the opposite of
current social media where it's like
this disconnection screaming across the
void it's like how do you bring people
together and have them see each other as
humans see the humanity even when we
can't because I don't like you right
like that it's like well we'll keep you
apart but you can see the humanity
everybody else like how do we actually
have an enjoyable conversation and how
do we make it effective so we can
eventually get other tech out of it
other stuff that is projects that are
that are world-changing and fixing the
worlds all at the same time
and six world brightest is my thing
ernesto says if your evil has a cure why
hurry if it does not why why hurry
I think he's responding to going south
yeah no I absolutely is the young but
you it's like I have a sense of urgency
and at the same time my sense of urgency
has calmed now that we're doing this
together and it's not just me it's huge
like it's like okay I feel like I was
doing it for so long just talking out
into the void hoping someone thought it
was like yes I see the beauty let's
create this we're only in a few weeks
but I guarantee you there's other people
who will come on board and fill in the
pieces were not able to fill in easily
ourselves and
it does get to a point where it's
snowballs and it's huge and everything
happens rather rather rapidly when it's
designed to do it that way and we're
keeping that in mind and yet no one gets
to decide somebody else has to move
rapidly right like the thing can move
rapidly we don't need to and I also just
had a thought on kind of starting to
build a list of participants did the did
the WordPress website is that up yet I
know the person who's doing it had a
sick kid and then she was sick but it's
supposed to be up in the next couple of
days
she's like learning WordPress while
she's doing it oh you sites and stuff so
like she's enjoying the learning of it
so that kind of that was again I have
zero experience in creating WordPress I
could barely do a blog on their site so
I needed someone to step in and do that
um it is up a little bit if you go to
together tech not with an aged Tec Tec
22 CH dot org then you can see a bit of
it there's a few things she has to fix
and there's like I have to move the blog
the actual blog over from I'm not gonna
move all of it over but the ones that
are pertinent to the actual together
tech it wasn't just my filler because I
wanted to do one a week for a few months
that I did that I'll be moving them over
from the the Wix website that is
currently and I do WordPress so if she
has any questions I think it's great
this is a great opportunity as a
learning thing as well we're all
learning different things how would I
get her in contact with you that might
actually if she's on like your email
Twitter or just email yeah feel free
Seema I know her she's one of the
Craigslist people a foot a few
craigslist ads out of my life and always
had like not always had but like some of
my favorite people I've met through
Craigslist like putting something out
into the void and been like like I've
met significant others one of my best
friends and we said a goal-setting group
and out a decade later we're like she's
coming over on Thursday she's an amazing
human it's it's been a like foundational
piece of my life because I have just
like put things out and then found
people and this was one of them I was
like is there anyone who's willing to
create a free website and she was so
awesome cool yeah yeah
that's a it's great project to learn on
I really have you suggest that yeah so
what I was thinking is that it'd be nice
to have kind of a landing page that we
could put our our elevator pitch that we
had last time which i think is good I
didn't have any suggestions except for
if we wanted to say intimate instead of
camera the word now what was it
meaningful are different I don't know
there makes that much difference
Oh Alan you yeah and then have an email
list signup form so for mail chip you
get for free you can get up to 20 emails
a month which wouldn't be sending emails
but I think you can have up to a
thousand people anyways she already I
wanted her to include like what I
couldn't do with Wix which I wanted to
do with WordPress is actually help
people sign up that being said together
Tech org is about together tech right I
don't even think it mentions idea cafe
because it was done long before I kind
of had the idea for the a cafe and so
adding another page or adding something
that is directly a part of that or a
page or maybe it's a separate one that
we've been linked to so yeah we do a one
page landing page that's free like free
to host somewhere that is because of my
technical skills I do free hosting on
github for small open source projects
which this equals but you do have to buy
a domain unless you want it under
something else and I was thinking just
as a starter I mean we could put a lei I
could put a landing page on Bentley
Davis calm or we could put on together
tech dot or just just to have some place
to go because I don't think we need to
like buy a domain and put it out there
unless we think it's we're at that point
and someone wants to pay the $79 or
something
I already did that with the other second
September to do this one I'm like that
was a big step for me I'm like I put
money because they up and put so much
time and
but I want to make sure that like
there's the threshold of people who want
to do what I want to risk luck I don't
have money to risk but it was also like
you know under 50 bucks let me do it and
that's why yeah for ideas at this stage
I generally suggest suggest that you
just with that we just put it on
something else and even both because we
could link to the same email list from
like my website and from or I come to
think of it if you if we get a free
MailChimp account or if she's I'm not
sure how she's doing the signups was
what are you thinking about okay
then we could also just get a link and
we can tweet it you don't even really
have to have a landing page and that
that elevator pitches is nice and
concise that will fit in a tweet with a
link so we don't even really need a
landing page but it might be good to set
one up shortly I know what I guess it's
not that great but the document I sent
out with the game be together tech sorry
idea cafe right was like it's kind of
like it's like here's what an idea Cafe
is here's what makes a meaningful
question it's maybe too much information
for a landing page but hey if you want
to participate in one here if you want
to watch them here right like a
breakdown of what it is I just want to
first acknowledge I would going I am not
reading the bottom one yet but uh for
your misspellings and that it's always
okay whether you speak English is your
second language whether you just miss
type like I understand your intent that
it's more about participation and
intense like that you're not you're not
trying to be an ass like that it's
nothing to do with it having a
misspelling but when someone's on here
trolling like there's certain things
that are like no you can be blocked but
offering your opinion and dissent is not
it yeah so far your your typos are less
frequent in English than mine are so
don't worry I don't
why do I need spellcheck it gets
horrific without it I like this UK or
necessary likes meaningful you can't be
meetings you can't be meeting full
without being intimate but you can be
intimate without being meaningful is I
think
yeah I mean I everything I have watched
meaningful videos but they have a
intimate conversation I think it's just
a small group of people but it's not a
big deal I think the phrasings I totally
get that
however there's like creative this thing
that helps grandpa solve his his
crossword puzzles so you can create the
rest of it and like I get annoyed by
everyone who's like running around with
a head like a chicken with her head cut
off trying to sell the world's problems
without taking a step back and creating
the tools that actually help solve the
problems because I think for me the only
way we are going to solve them is
together is with like this non
hierarchical like how does somebody say
what they need how do we get somebody to
get on board with climate change without
screaming at them that like climate
change is real if they don't believe in
it how do we get them to understand it
and so the foundation is we need a way
to have a conversation we need a way to
bring people together we need a way to
be able to tap into we have it like we
have enough intellect we have enough
stuff we have enough everything we need
to solve the world's problems it's just
not organized and so organizing that and
being able to create the tools that help
people find their space in the solution
offered is the solution like it
literally is like then you're tapping
into a fraction of human potential it
rapidly snowballs and everyone solves
everything especially when you're you're
owning that it's not perfect right that
like the more you're able to say okay
well what didn't what if this isn't your
place why isn't it right if it's just as
simple as adding a new tool let's add it
if it's we're fundamentally opposed cuz
you want to create an oil company and
make billions of dollars this isn't the
place for you right like this is like a
voluntary how we cooperate in creating a
solution to all of the world's problems
which are all interconnected and you
can't really change one without changing
another you need to kind of solve
poverty and climate change and
misinformation and all
stuff simultaneously you need a tech
cooperative to do that in my opinion and
so we're creating that's a cooperative
within our capacity of the people
involved right so listen
alright so out five minutes
I'm just was just gonna say so I'm gonna
take on take on I'd reconnecting with a
person doing the website just to make
sure that yes that is is on the way
connect to you choose if she has further
further conversation it might be that
she passes it off to you right and not
in I don't know or like it's like hey I
bought it this far I I don't have the
skills to get further or she might
really appreciate having that that
guidance because she is learning it
right and she no longer has a job so
she's like I can focus on this she's
just a way for a week visiting people
older so I was like awesome that's great
and so I think having like I can't help
her with that in fact a lot of the time
she's like can you add me this and like
I don't even know how to do that I have
to watch like three YouTube videos to
figure that out and owning that that's
why I had someone step in to create the
WordPress because I can't and Wix wasn't
making them isn't meeting the needs of
SEO and email lists and that kind of
thing so that's what I'm taking on it's
just connecting with her as well as
being part of those five conversations I
was talking about the idea cafe I'm
doing that which is for our project and
meeting with my brother to like move
kind of the idea cafe YouTube channels
like how to get more subscribers or how
to like I don't know build it how did
and just how to help him with his
project and get other people on board to
have a conversation about other projects
that are already underway right without
having to reinvent the wheel and we're
having a Baba Omega rule meeting of like
practicing Omega rule which will be
meeting for the first time next week
which should be cool and then
participating in future thinkers Monday
conversation
so those are my conversations at this
yeah your brother yeah for your brothers
one I've watched a couple those I do
have some suggestions for them and I
actually know a guy in the UK it was a
similar goal probably you know different
techniques and stuff
so I don't I I might be available I'm
not sure when y'all are doing that if
you want me to be live or if yeah if you
wanna think on one of them you said
there was a way to get in touch with
them but I'd be happy to hop on and and
we'd do it two hours before this
tomorrow
so like 11:00 a.m. your time 9:00 a.m.
our time yeah so if you want to shoot me
a link or you want to be on video right
I can yep yeah okay I have so much
support now like between you and just
Gabey and like the Internet I'm like I
kind of don't need to focus on my
project I want to figure out there's
also someone on Twitter that I think is
game be that I wanted to reach out to
and say hey do you want to come have
your project be part of it right like
the more people there are that are able
to get crowd solution like peer
solutions and crowd solutions right the
faster these things get made and the
more we showcase what cooperation is
right you succeed in as nice is all of
us succeeding and there's something very
real in this space about like that
like it honestly if someone came and
stole our idea made the idea cafe
tomorrow let's move on to the app one
right like it's like it's not great it
exists if you make it for profit it's
Google you've broken it so that doesn't
work but right if somebody else makes
and it's open source and it's
transparent or even if it's a piece of
it we can use it to create our
transparent democratic thing awesome
that's why we're using Facebook and
YouTube and stream yard and all the
tools that we we can use and yes what
are you taking on for the next week so I
will do some research on different
technologies that might fit these
requirements for our V 1 or V v2
actually I don't know your v-0 it
doesn't matter
I'm giving names when they're not
important so yeah so I'll look at
technologies I think that'll be my only
real takeaway I might play around with
making a landing page either on like my
Bentley Davis side or something just as
a showcase and then you know when I get
the contact from your friend that's
doing the for me contact for the
WordPress side I'll see what ever she
needs and help her out
have you checked out the Wix website the
one that is from my Twitter yeah I saw
it
yeah I saw it I don't remember it now I
do remember looking at here looks like
it's been months since I touched it as
far as updating it and there's been so
many updates in me that I'm like oh this
is outdated but also it's just the
concept of like having a democratic
transparent company that we all owned
together that saves the world and then
it's so focused on intellect like on the
like history science I was like oh
that's not my focus anymore now it's
more on the connection and because once
we have that we can allow geeks to geek
out in the area of their choosing and
all benefit and then have yeah that it's
like it doesn't even include the idea
cafe it doesn't include I might include
Yelp for ABS because that was kind of
more of a but like not the true
potential in it of like bringing people
together and creating it in a way that
is helping their projects and helps us
disseminate trust between us right of
like how do we trust you if you have one
so yeah else and I'll send you the link
for tomorrow it'll be great all right
awesome and if you wanted to invite the
person from the UK we could just I'll
let my brother know I mean that might be
preempted
no that's he's that's not might be a
better time we had scheduling
difficulties and we yeah it is like one
morning I think it's time if he's in the
UK I think there eight hours wait ahead
there the other way okay but two bits on
family will start with me and I might
just get them in touch you know so
offline they can coordinator or
something I think they won't find each
other's projects interesting yeah which
is also part of it I'm not great at that
but Ramsey's good at that of like hey
have you heard of this project that's
why I hope we have the spreadsheet that
neither of us have touched of like prod
things that thing's cool Saints that I
want to be able to keep in my head that
I can possibly keep in my head so thank
you not reach out to them
alright thank you this was great I will
see you tomorrow
I will see you everyone else next week
at this time period to perfect the world
Friday's love and am alright